Finding aid for WUOM Records, 1914-1982
Bentley Historical Library
- Paper Records, 1920s-1970s
  - Manager's Files
    - E.G. Burrows, 1957-1972
      - National Educational Radio (NER) (cont.)
        - Wingspread Conference on Educational Radio as a National Resource, September 1966
          - Correspondence, June-October 1966 (Box 3)
          - Planning Materials (Box 3)
          - Pre-conference Correspondence (Box 3)
          - Publicity (Box 3)
          - Reports and Addresses (Box 3)
        - Public Broadcasting Act of, 1967
          - Burrows Public Statements (Box 4)
          - Burrows Reference Files (Box 4)
          - Correspondence (Box 4)
          - Memoranda to Executive Committee re: S. 1160 (Box 4)
          - NER Memoranda and Press Releases (Box 4)
          - Testimonies in Support of H.R. 6736 (Box 4)
          - Testimonies in Support of S. 1160, 2 folders (Box 4)
        - Reorganizational Study, 1967 (Box 4)
        - Bound Volume
          - Memos to Managers, 1964-1969 (Box 4)
      - WUOM
        - Awards (American Federation for the Blind; Armstrong Memorial Research Foundation) (Box 4)
        - Correspondence, 1960s (Box 4)
        - FCC Inquiry re: Revision of FM Broadcasting Rules (correspondence and reference materials), 1966-1967 (Box 4)
        - NAEB Educational Communications Systems (ECS) Project, 1964-1966
          - Correspondence (Box 4)
          - Midwest Feasibility Model (Box 4)
          - Reports and Memoranda (Box 4)
        - One Nation Indivisible, 1956-1958
          - Correspondence (Box 4)
          - Grant Request and Administrative Records (Box 4)
          - Press Releases and Publicity (Box 4)
        - Original Productions
          - The American Town: A Self-Portrait (Box 4)
          - Michigan Names (Box 4)
          - News in Twentieth Century America (Box 4)
          - Orestes (Box 4)
        - Press Releases, 1957-1967 (scattered dates) (Box 4)
        - Program Summaries (monthly reports), 1968-1970; 3 folders (Box 4)
        - Response to NER Survey, 1966 (Box 4)
        - Survey of Radio Stations using WUOM Distributed Programming, 1965 (Box 4)
        - Tenth Anniversary, July 5, 1958 (Box 4)
      - WVGR
        - Clippings, 1961-1962 (Box 4)
        - Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 4)
        - Dedication Program, December 9, 1961 (Box 4)
        - Programming Proposals (Box 4)
        - Publicity and Promotion, 1961-1962 (Box 4)
    - Neal Bedford (1972-1984)
      - Publicity (Box 4)
  - Radio Classroom
    Radio Classroom series (.5 linear ft.). For twenty years (1951-1971) WUOM was a leader in offering radio instruction to schools in the State of Michigan. Though the size and depth of this series in no way reflect the influence enjoyed by the programs in the Radio Classroom series, it is significant that the bulk of the records document the development of the first and most popular of the programs, "Festival of Song." Taught by faculty in the School of Music, "Festival" was offered from October through April to schools desiring classroom music instruction. Included in the records are scripts and performance notes, and programs, correspondence, itineraries, and related materials concerning the program's annual spring tour.
    - "Festival of Song"
      - Correspondence, 1960-1971 (scattered dates) (Box 5)
      - Correspondence (Department of Defense Overseas Dependents Schools), 1967-1970 (Box 5)
      - Grant Application (Tahquamenon [Michigan] Area School District) (Box 5)
      - Lesson Plans and Performance Notes (Box 5)
      - Miscellaneous (journal notes, student artwork, resource lists, etc.) (Box 5)
      - Scripts, 1967/68-1970/71; 7 folders (Box 5)
      - Spring Tour, 1951-1971; 7 folders (Box 5)
      - Survey of Participating Schools, ca., 1971 (Box 5)
    - "The Great Lakes"
      - Teacher's Guides (Box 5)
    - Publicity, 1951-1953; undated (Box 5)
    - School Radio Programs [teacher's guides] (bound), 1953/54-1954/55; 1 volume
      - "Festival of Song" (Box 5)
      - "Meeting the Situation" [non-WUOM] (Box 5)
      - "Learning Outdoors" (Box 5)
      - "Tales of the Talking Stone" (Box 5)
      - "Sky Trails" (Box 5)
      - "Milestones of Freedom" (Box 5)
      - Piano Accompaniment for "Festival of Song" (Box 5)
      - "A Name to Remember" (Box 5)
      - "Messages and Men" (Box 5)
      - "Red Man in Michigan" (Box 5)
      - "Our Schools" (Box 5)
      - "Visitons Mimi" [French language course] (Box 5)
      - "Adventures in Research" (Box 5)
      - "Story Time" (Box 5)
      - "Vacation Land" (Box 5)
  - Radio Scripts [bound]
    Radio Scripts series (9 linear ft.). Both bound and unbound, these consist of original scripts produced and broadcast by WUOM staff and transcripts of talks given by University of Michigan faculty. The "pre-WUOM" scripts date from the early 1930s to 1946 and chiefly consist of faculty radio talks. The "WUOM" scripts primarily correspond to the original dramatic/documentary program series produced by WUOM in the late 1940s to mid-1950s. The bulk of the scripts are in bound volumes.
    - Pre-WUOM
      - Children's Radio Programs [dramatizations of children's literature], ca., 1940s (Box 6)
      - Mimeographed Radio Talks of [selection based on listener response], 1933-1934 (Box 6)
      - Radio Art Programs ca., 1932-1941 (Box 6)
      - "An Art Pilgrimage to Famous Museums," programs #2-9, 11-19 (Box 6)
      - "American History as Told by American Artists," programs #1-19 (Box 6)
      - "Art Appreciation Series," programs #1-5 (Box 6)
      - "Union Pacific,", 1938 (Box 6)
        (Paramount Pictures script signed by C.B. DeMille, Barbara Stanwyck, Joel McCrea, Akim Tamiroff, Robert Preston, and Lynne Overman)
      - University of Michigan Broadcast Service (Box 6)
        (Publicity, 1933-1936 Forestry, Economic Stability and Unemployment Relief; Child's Own Bookshelf; Problems and Methods of Character Education; Economic Series of 1931-32; Art Appreciation Series, 1932-33)
      - University of Michigan Original Radio Plays, 1946 (Box 6)
      - University of Michigan Radio Medical Talks, Vol. 1, circa 1932-1941 (Box 6)
      - University of Michigan Radio Medical Talks, 1942-1943 (Box 7)
      - University of Michigan Radio Plays: Adaptations [excerpts from classic fiction], undated (Box 7)
      - University of Michigan Radio Programs: Dramatized Legal Information
        - "From Legal History,", 1941 (Box 7)
        - "Out of Court,", undated (Box 7)
      - University of Michigan Radio Programs [series]
        - "Game of the Week,", 1939-1940 (Box 7)
        - "Know Your [Michigan] Cities,", 1940-1941 (Box 7)
        - "Tell Me, Professor,", 1943-1944 (Box 7)
        - "It's the Bunk" [superstitions], 1940 (Box 7)
        - "World Masterpieces: Nineteen Quiz Programs on Music and Literature,", 1946-1947 (Box 7)
      - University of Michigan Radio Talks, 23 volumes
        - Anthropology, Archaeology, Botany, Landscape Design, Geology, Zoology, ca., 1930-1942 (Box 7)
      - Architecture, Economics, Languages, Mathematics, Sociology, ca., 1931-1939 (Box 8)
      - Astronomy; Botany; Chemistry; Dentistry; Nursing; Pharmacy, ca., 1930s-1940s (Box 8)
      - Clements Library; English; Hobby Series; Living for Moderns; Medical Series, 1947-48; Social Service; Sponsored Research; English Engineering; Miscellaneous (Box 8)
      - English; English Engineering (Box 8)
      - Engineering Series, ca., 1931-1942 (Box 8)
      - Forestry and Conservation, ca., 1930-1941 (Box 8)
      - Guidance, Delinquency, Children's Problems, ca., 1935-1944 (Box 9)
      - Historical Dramas, ca. "Little Known Facts in American History;" "It Happened Before" (World War II Series), 1938-1942 (Box 9)
      - Home Planning Series, Fall 1935 Medical Series, 1945-1946, 1935-1946 (Box 9)
      - Literature Series; Forensic Series (Box 9)
      - Marital Relations Series; Health Series; Pharmacy Series (Box 9)
      - Medical Series, 1946-1947 (Box 9)
      - Michigan, My Michigan, 1934-1936; 2 volumes (Box 9)
      - Parent Education Programs: Mental Hygiene of Adolescence; Adult Education; Vocational Guidance; Speech; Language, 1934-1935 (Box 9)
      - Parent Education Programs: Michigan, My Michigan; Geography and Travel; Eras in English Literature; Critical Moments in the Lives of Nations; Home Planning, Building and Maintenance; Current Events and University Research, 1935-1936 (Box 9)
      - Pharmacy, Physics, History, Business Administration, Economics, and Finance, 1946-1947 (Box 10)
      - Speech, Dramatics (Box 10)
      - Speech, Journalism, Political Science, ca., 1934-1938 (Box 10)
      - Vocational Guidance, 2 volumes (Box 10)
      - Youth Delinquency; Guidance; Health; Michigan, My Michigan (Box 10)
      - Writers' War Board: Radio Plays, 1942-1946 (Box 10)
    - WUOM
      - "American Industry;" "Sky Trails;" "Soo Adventure,", 1950-1954 (Box 11)
      - "A Gallery of Women;" "Julius Caesar;" "Learning Outdoors,", 1951-1954 (Box 11)
      - "The Golden Queen,", 1951-1952 (Box 11)
      - "Michigan Names;" "The Tunnelers,", 1959-1960 (Box 11)
      - "A Name to Remember (national);" "The Musicmakers,", 1951-1952 (Box 11)
      - "One Nation Indivisible,", 1957-1958 (Box 11)
      - "Panorama,", 1956/57-1960/61; 3 volumes (Box 12)
      - Radio Guild Dramas, 1952-1957 (Box 12)
      - Radio Medical Series, 1948-1956; 2 volumes (Box 12)
      - "Rx for Health," Miscellaneous Programs, 1956-1963; 3 volumes (Box 13)
      - "Tales of the Valiant,", 1955 (Box 13)
      - "They Fought Alone,", 1953 (Box 13)
      - "Treasures Off the Shelf,", 1949 (Box 13)
  - Radio Scripts [unbound]
    - Pre-WUOM
      - "American Revolution" [drama], ca., 1938 (Box 14)
      - "Heroes of Medicine" [drama], February-April 1942 (Box 14)
      - "Hobby Series,", Undated (Box 14)
      - "Hymns of All Churches,", September-October 1938 (Box 14)
      - Miscellaneous, 1939; 1946
        - Interview with Edward W. Blakeman, March 9, 1939 (Box 14)
        - University of Michigan Anniversary Program, March 18, 1939 (Box 14)
        - [Campus news summary], April 1946 (Box 14)
        - Special Laboratory Program (University of Michigan and CBS, co-producers): "Ex-Soldier;", August 16, 1944 (Box 14)
      - Talks by University of Michigan Faculty, 1930s-1940s; Undated (Box 14)
      - "Vocational Guidance Series,", 1940-1941 (Box 14)
      - "The World This Week" (Preston Slosson), April 27, 1941 (Box 14)
      - "A Dickens of a Christmas,", December 24, 1970 (Box 14)
      - "Messages and Men," programs #1-7, 9-13 (Box 14)
      - Michigan Union Dedication Program ["Sesquicentennial"], October 1954 (Box 14)
      - "Money, Machines, and Music," programs #1-10, 13, 1964 (Box 14)
      - "A Name to Remember" [Michigan], programs #1-28, 3 folders (Box 14)
      - "The News from Dallas,", November 1964 (Box 14)
      - "Radio Guild," programs #1, 3-7, 12, 1951-1952 (Box 14)
      - "To Make Men Free," programs #1-[3] (Box 14)
      - "Toward Peace," programs #1-15 (Box 14)
      - "[Tribute to] Waldo Abbot,", November 4, 1964 (Box 14)
    - WUOM: Program Series
      - "Union Voices," programs #1-26 (Box 14)
      - "Musical Playhouse": Showboat (Box 14)
  - Visual Material
    Visual Material (1.25 linear ft. and 1 outsize volume). Although including photographs--mostly pertaining to "Festival of Song" tours, this series consists predominantly of scrapbooks which, through newspaper clippings and other promotional material, document WUOM's broadcast activity from the 1940s through the 1960s.
    Sound Reels: Accompanying Materials (.25 linear ft.). Press releases, announcers' cue sheets, news clippings and other materials which were used by WUOM staff in broadcast production, and which provide helpful background and/or summary information regarding the recordings. Originally stored with individual sound reels, they have been removed and filed separately for preservation reasons.
    - Photographs
      - Awards and Programs
        - "Festival of Song" (6 envelopes)
          - Adult Performers (Box 14)
          - Candid Portraits and Audiences (Box 14)
          - Children Performers (Box 14)
          - [Spring] Festival, 1953 (Box 14)
          - [Spring] Festival, 1960 (Box 14)
          - Negatives (Box 14)
      - WVGR Dedication (Box 14)
    - Scrapbooks
      - "News in 20th Century America", 3 folders (Box 14)
      - "They Fought Alone", 1 volume (Box 15)
      - "Treasures Off the Shelf", 1 volume (Box 15)
      - Broadcasting Service of the University of Michigan, 1925-1950; 1 volume (Box 15)
      - Clippings, 1952; 1 folder (Box 15)
        (loose, from WUOM Clipping Scrapbook, 1948-1951
      - [WUOM], 1952-1969; 2 folders (Box 15)
      - [WUOM Clipping Scrapbook], 1948-1951 (Box 15)
      - Scrapbook, "The Michigan Radio Classroom,", 1953 (Volume 1)
        (BImu/C471)
  - Sound Reels: Accompanying Materials
    - Sound Reels (7-inch)
      - Cue sheets, press releases, and clippings, 1960s (Box 16)
        (for reels R59A-R149A)
    - Sound Reels (10 ½"), 2 folders
      - Cue sheets, press releases, and clippings, 1960s-1970s (Box 16)
        (for reels R159B-R284B)
- Audio Material, 1930s-1970s
  Ranging in date from the 1930s into the 1980s, the sound recordings have been arranged first by format into two groups, sound reels and sound discs; the sound reels have been further arranged by size. Thus, there are three separate series of sound recordings: sound reels (7-inch); sound reels (10 1/2-inch); and sound discs. The recordings within each series have been arranged by provenance and content into the following subseries:
  WUOM: Anniversaries and Dedication Programs
  WUOM: Original Productions, 1949-1967
  WUOM: Program Series, 1948-1990
  U-M Ceremonies and Convocations, 1961-1969
  U-M Conferences and Lectures, 1961-1969
  U-M History, 1958, 1961
  U-M Sesquicentennial Celebration, 1967
  State and Local History and Events, 1950, 1960, undated
  Each recording has been assigned an inventory number which is listed in brackets following the item description in the boxlist. This number designates whether the recording is a reel (prefix "R") or a disc (prefix "D"), the recording's numeric sequence, and, for sound reels, the size ("A" for 7", "B" for 10 ½"). Unless otherwise noted, reel playback speed is 7 ½ inches per second (ips).
  - Audition Copies
    Audition Copies (.75 linear ft.). Select sound reels have been duplicated as cassettes for the use of researchers. Audition copies include such heavily used recordings as John F. Kennedy's speeches in Ann Arbor on October 13-14, 1960, and Lyndon B. Johnson's 1964 "Great Society" commencement address. (Numbers in brackets indicate corresponding sound reel[s])
    - Fonda, Jane, December 1, 1970; [R234B] (Box 16)
    - Johnson, Lyndon B., Commencement, May 22, 1964; [R182B] (Box 16)
    - Kennedy, John F., at Michigan Union, October 13-14, 1960; [R147A-R148A]; 2 audiocassettes (Box 16)
    - Kennedy, John F., leaving Ann Arbor, October 14, 1960; [R149A] (Box 16)
    - McNamara, Robert S., Commencement, June 12, 1962; [R181B] (Box 16)
    - Murrow, Edward R., Commencement, June 17, 1961; [R96A-R97A] (Box 16)
    - Roethke: A Tribute, [R15A-R16A] (Box 16)
    - Warfield, William, Music School, August 12, 1985 (Box 16)
    - Taylor, Billy, Music Schol, August 12, 1985 (Box 16)
    - Poetry reading, January 24, 1986 (Box 16)
      (Seamus Heaney, Galway Kinnell, Donald Hall, Wendell Berry)
  - Sound Reels (7-inch)
    [Access to digital audio files currently restricted to Bentley Library reading room]
    - WUOM: Anniversary and Dedication Programs
      WUOM: Anniversaries and Dedication Programs consist of recordings of programs produced to commemorate special events in the history of radio station WUOM.
      - Dedication Program: Silver Anniversary of University of Michigan Broadcasting Service and Dedication of WUOM and New Studios, broadcast, January 14, 1950; [R1A] (Box 17)
        (dub November 16, 1964)
    - WUOM: Original Productions
      The subseries WUOM: Original Productions is comprised of recordings of dramatic and/or documentary programs or program series written, performed, and produced by WUOM staff, often in conjunction with university faculty and students. Except in a very few instances, only a representative sampling of recordings were retained for each series. Items of uncertain date or undated are listed first.
      - Archives Anthology ([R2A]), [between 1950 and 1959]; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 3 3/4 ips (Box 17)
        - [Part 1], [8738-SR-1-1-1]; (Radio program wherein E. Burroughs interviews Eleanor Steber of the Metropolitan Opera, U-M football player Willie Heston, poet Ogden Nash; Louis Elbel, writer of "The Victors"; Dramatization -- J Fred Lawton as Yost; Lawton and Earl Moore discus writing of Varsity.)
      - Charles Ives Dared / E.G. Burrows; Leonard Bernstein; New York Philharmonic Orchestra ([R3A]), [between 1950 and 1959]; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 15 ips (Box 17)
        - [Part 1], [8738-SR-2-1-1]; (Biographical Tribute to American Composer, Charles Ives. Reading with musical accompaniment starring Charles Ives, Leonard Bernstein with the New York Philharmonic and E.G. Burrows as Charlton Heston.)
      - Ralph Johnson interviews Harriet Arnow ([R4A-R5A]), 1969 March 28; 2 Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 17)
        - [Reel 1, Part 1], [8738-SR-3-1-1]; (Tape 1; Informal Interview recorded by Ralph Johnson in Harriet Arnow's home, mainly about the problems of Appalachia with reminiscences of her early life.)
        - [Reel 2 Part 1], [8738-SR-3-2-1]; (Tape 2; Informal Interview recorded by Ralph Johnson in Harriet Arnow's home, mainly about the problems of Appalachia with reminiscences of her early life.)
      - May Festival Interview: Eugene Ormandy with E.G. Burroughs ([R6A]), 1968 April 22; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 17)
        - [Part 1], [8738-SR-4-1-1]; (E.G. Burroughs interviews conductor Eugene Ormandy, recording also includes statement by Jesse Norman.)
      - Michigan Week, 1959-1968
        - Michigan Week: Interview with F. Clever Bald ([R7A]), 1959 April 30; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 17)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-5-1-1]; (Interview of F. Clever Bald about the history of the Michigan Historical Collections. Bald was director of the Collections from 1960-1966. Broadcast in May of 1959)
        - Michigan Week: Full Employment in Michigan report by William Haber, ([R8A]), 1960 April 29; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 17)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-5-2-1]; (Report by William Haber on Michigan's economy and jobs, broadcast May 19, 1960.)
        - Michigan Week: Tribute to Chase Osborn ([R9A]), 1960 April 30; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 15 ips (Box 17)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-5-3-1]; (Broadcast May 1960 for Michigan week, a radio tribute to Chase Osborn former Governor, UM regent, and explorer.)
        - Michigan Week 1960: Michigan Folk Songs ([R10A]), 1960 May 02; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 15 ips (Box 17)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-5-4-1]; (Broadcast May 1960; Michigan, My Michigan performed; Ivan Walton interviewed, Lumberjack songs; Boardman River sung by Bill Binder; The Schooner Hume sung by Ed Vinderburg; Red Iron Ore unknown musicians; concluded with Michigan, My Michigan.)
        - Michigan Week 1961: Red Man in Michigan; Michigan Geology ([R11A]), 1961 May 10; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 17)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-5-5-1]; (Red Man in Michigan #1: The Tribes: Radio program includes excerpts of Native American music, excerpts from interviews with Native Americans, different tribes history. Michigan Geology: Interview with Don Eschman and Jack Dorr on geologic history of Michigan and scenic sights residents can see.)
        - Michigan Week 1962: Programs 2, 4 and 6 ([R12A]), Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 17)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-5-7-1]; (Program #2 Interview with James Wilson on Institute of Science and Technology at Michigan. Program#4 Interviewed of Prof. Hausel on highways in Michigan, Interview #6 Interview of Robert Warner on topic of Steven T. Mason papers acquired by Michigan Historical Collections. Steven T. Mason, the "boy governor" was the first Governor of Michigan.)
        - Michigan Week 1964: Michigan's Economy: interview with Roblee Martin ([R14A]), 1964 May 11; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 15 ips (Box 17)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-5-11-1]; (President of the Dundee Cement Company Roblee Martin discusses economic development and research in Michigan.)
        - Michigan Week 1965: Theodore Roethke: A Tribute ([R15A-R16-A]), 1965 May 12; 2 Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 17)
          - [Reel 1, Part 1], [8738-SR-5-12-1]; (Tape 1; A Tribute to Theodore Roethke with E.G. Burrows, host; Allan Seeger; Donald Hall; A.J.M. Smith; Nelson Bentley; broadcast May 23, 1965.)
          - [Reel 2, Part 1], [8738-SR-5-13-1]; (Tape 2; A Tribute to Theodore Roethke with E.G. Burrows, host; Allan Seeger; Donald Hall; A.J.M. Smith; Nelson Bentley; broadcast May 23, 1965.)
        - Michigan Week 1966: Michigan Folk Songs 1966 ([R17A]), 1966 May 03; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 17)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-5-14-1]; (Tape 1; Michigan Folk Songs broadcast May 18, 1966, excerpts of: My Mother Stood on the Liverpool Dock, John A. Williams; Don't Go Down the Mine, Daddy, John A. Williams; Haste to the Wedding, (Instrumental) played by Michigan Lumberjacks; Widecombe Fair; She Cost Me Seven and Six Pence, And Shall Trelawney Die sung by Frederick Calhart. Doug Fulton, broadcast May 17, 1966, on conservation issues in Michigan, Deer population, hunting, and fishing in Michigan)
        - Michigan Week 1966: Michigan's Natural Resources and Conservation: interview with Archibald B. Cowan ([R13A]), 1966 May 08; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 17)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-5-10-1]; (On Michigan's environmental issues; population growth, outdoor recreation, water pollution, industrial use of resources)
        - Michigan Week 1966: Sesquicentennial at University of Michigan ([R18A]), 1966 May 17, 19; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 17)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-5-16-1]; (Sesquicentennial at University of Michigan broadcast May 19, 1966; Cooperative Educational Ventures broadcast May 17, 1966, on celebrations and conferences for alumni and public for the Sesquicentennial.)
        - Michigan Week 1966: Chief Herbert Welsh ([R19A]), 1966 May 21; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 17)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-5-18-1]; (Tape 3; Interview with Chief Herbert Welsh, broadcast May 21, 1966. Interviewed at home, Herbert Walsh was a Sioux descendent of Sitting Bull.)
      - "Tales of the Valiant" broadcast, October-December 1955; 1 reels
        (award-winning drama-documentary, scripts available in WUOM paper record series; 1 reel of [13 retained])
        - "Tales of the Valiant" Program #13: José Rizal [Philippines], ([R20A]), Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7-1/2 ips (Box 17)
          - [Part 1], [8738-SR-6-1-1]; (Radio program on José Rizal, Filipino nationalist and revolutionary.)
      - "To the Cornflower and the Maize,"
        (Oral history-documentary produced for University of Michigan Sesquicentennial] recorded 1965-1966, broadcast weekly beginning January 1967. Traces the historical development of the university from founding to the 1950s)
        - To the Cornflower and the Maize Program #1: "The Classical Greek on the Old Frontier" ([R21A]), 1965 November 24; Audio Reel-to-Reel, 7 inch, 7 1/2 ips (Box 17)